GOKTUG OZATES

Maintenance Specialist

+905068680451 goktug.ozates0@gmail.com Ankara - Turkey 🧥 linkedin.com/in/goktug-ozates

Professional Summary

Ingenious and determined mechanical maintenance specialist with over 4 years of experience in several sectors. Eager to use and implement first-class maintenance skills to provide the system safety with experience in asset management and analysis methods.

Work Experience

Senior Specialist Engineer

Mar 2022 - Present

BEKO, Ankara - TURKEY

- Achieved 5% increase electrical energy efficiency procured leak detection service on air pressure systems all over the plant by using 6 sigma.
- Implemented new CMMS onto maintenance strategy to track reactive maintenance records that provides making RCA and create planned maintenance by being supplied all the requirements all the year round.
- Carrying out CAPEX projects that yearly provide reductions of electrical energy consumption about \$ 200K.
- Led and managed daily a maintenance team of 45 to solve faults and make improvements on the manufacturing process.

Mechanical Maintenance Engineer

Jul 2019 - Mar 2022

ERDEMIR, Zonguldak - TURKEY

- Organized asset management (creating preventive maintenance) depending on KPI data by using IBM Maximo.
- İnvolved 14 Kaizen projects and carried out 5S methodology on the workshops, facilities and offices.
- Planned maintenance schedule during overhauls and manage team, usage of supplied spare parts and subcontractors.
- Achieved an OPEX project with an engineer team increasing efficiency of a gas turbine by cooling the body and nearly saved \$180K for a year.

Internships – Tool Design Engineer

May 2016 - Aug 2016

TurkTraktor, Ankara – TURKEY

- Designing gauges used in production for quality assurance on Creo 3 parametric,
- Designing tools to assemble components each other,
- Providing to keep process going trouble-shooting.

Internships - Manufacturing Engineer

Savronik, Ankara - TURKEY

Feb 2016 - May 2016

Internships – Tool Design Engineer Mesa Imalat, Ankara - TURKEY

May 2014 - Aug 2014

Education

TOBB University Graduated 2017 Degree: BSc. Mechanical Engineering GPA:2.65

Obuda University Erasmus Programme 2015

Mechanical Engineering

Skills

- RCM - Hydraulics - Basic PLC Prog.

- PPM - Pneumatics - P&ID

- TPM - Catia V5 - Kaizen

- 6 Sigma GB - FMEA - 5S

Certifications

6 Sigma Green Belt Certificate Beko, Jun 2023

Siemens S7-1200 programing Certificate Udemy, Sep 2022

Energy Management Certificate Ministry of Energy, Jun 2020

Projects

- Saving electrical energy by using 6sigma Beko, May 2023
- Increasing efficiency with gas turbine body cooling Erdemir, Dec 2021
- Designing a new lumbar corpectomy cage for graduation project TOBB University, May 2017